Finding Aid for Clarence T. Johnston Papers, 1888-1941
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Camp Davis Summer Surveying Camp Photos 1911-1928
  - 1927 Session
    - Camp Davis from Grapevine Point (Box 9:7)
    - Beaver Dam on Carp Creek viewed from below (Box 9:7)
    - Camp Davis from high ground W of harbor (Box 9:7)
    - State St. looking W from point near E end of camp (Box 9:7)
      [74]
  - 1928 Session
    - The proposed campsite looking SE from a point near log house. (Box 9:7)
      (The remains of the fence in the foreground marks the approximate boundary of the tract. The timber shown in the picture is all on the slope of the mountain which rises abruptly from the valley. A small stream runs from the mountain near the middle of the picture and flows across the camp site. The valley land in the foreground is covered with a growth of grass and low sage brush)
    - Looking W from a point near log house (Box 9:7)
      (same point from which [1] was taken, showing log house in foreground; barn to the right and a portion of the valley lands and lower slopes of the mountain)
    - View from the campsite (Box 9:7)
      (This is a view of the campsite looking S from the highway which runs along the N side of the valley. The Hoback River is in the middle of the picture. The house and barn located on the lands recommended are beyond the river and at the foot of the mountain slope)
    - Looking SE the campsite (Box 9:7)
      (from same point from which [3] was taken)
    - Looking E from the campsite (Box 9:7)
      (same point from which [3] and [4] were taken. The main highway running to Yellowstone Park from Rock Springs is shown on the left of the view. The road leaving this to enter the campsite crosses the middle of the picture and runs to the right. The Hoback Canyon is at the left of the center of the picture)
    - Looking SW from the campsite (Box 9:7)
      (from same point [3-5] were taken)
    - Looking W along the Hoback Valley (Box 9:7)
      (from the same point from which [3-6] were taken. The main highway running from Rook Springs to Yellowstone Park is shown on right margin of the picture. The telephone line connecting Jackson with the campsite and the Forest Ranger Station a mile beyond is also shown)
    - View taken from point near house on recommended campsite showing quaking aspen trees at the base of slope of mountain (Box 9:7)
    - View taken from point between log house and river, showing barn and country beyond, looking W (Box 9:7)
    - View of Hoback River looking upstream and E from point near E boundary of proposed campsite (Box 9:7)
    - The Hoback River looking downstream W from a point near E boundary of proposed campsite (Box 9:7)
    - The Teton Mountains looking W from junction of main N and S highway and road from Jenny Lake. (Box 9:7)
      (Clouds partly obscure the summit of the Grand Teton. The top, of Mt. Owen is just visible to the right. The trees in the foreground indicate the location of Cottonwood Creek which drains Leigh and Jenny Lakes. It flows S or to the left. Taken on Wed., August 22 at 4:20 pm)
      (Print 23 instead of this)
    - The Teton Mountains looking SW (Box 9:7)
      (Taken from the same point as [12] looking SW instead of W. Taken Wed., August 22 at 4:20 pm)
    - Mount Moran and a little of Jackson Lake viewed from Jackson Lake Lodge, looking W. Wed., August 22 at 8:30 am (Box 9:7)
    - The Grand Teton and other mountains of the Teton Range looking SW across Jackson Lake. Wed., August 22, '28, 8:30 am (Box 9:7)
    - The Gros Ventre slide looking SW from road on N side of canyon. (Box 9:7)
      (The view is taken from a point E (upstream) from the slide)
    - The Gros Ventre slide looking SE from N end of slide. A small section of the lake created by the slide is shown at extreme right (Box 9:7)
    - The Gros Ventre slide same as [17] except the view is more to the S (Box 9:7)
    - The Gros Ventre slide looking S from N end of slide and N slope of canyon. (Box 9:7)
      (The highest point from which slide came is 1/2 mile above the river and 1 1/2 miles away. The slide is 1 1/4 miles wide at the foot of the slope. This occurred in the spring of 1926. During the high water, spring of 1927 the top 80 feet of this natural dam was washed away and seven people were drowned in the valley below. Much property was destroyed. Taken on Thursday, August 23, '28.)
    - View of campsite looking W from near log house. Friday morning, August 24, '28 (Box 9:7)
    - Campsite looking E. Hoback Canyon left of center. Main highway, Rock Springs to Yellowstone Park near left margin-N side Hoback River. August 24, '28 (Box 9:7)
    - Stream which would supply water for power and domestic purposes. At campsite looking almost E from a point not far from log house, Friday, August 24 (Box 9:7)
    - The Teton Mountains looking W from junction of main N and S highway and road from Jenny Lake. (Box 9:7)
      (Same as [12] except with different stop and exposure. August 24 [This is the better])
      [231]
    - Looking up Gros Ventre Canyon from SE part of Sec. 36. Tp. 43 N.R. 115 W. (Box 9:7)
      (The Gros Ventre slide is right of center. The rim channel at center shows the effects of the flood of 1927. Section 36 was inspected as a possible campsite. It is unsatisfactory in many ways. The land could be purchased from the state of Wyoming, at $10.00 per acre. Tuesday, August 21, '28. 3:00 pm)
    - Looking up Gros Ventre Canyon from SE part of Sec. 36. Tp. 43 N.R. 115 W. (Box 9:7)
      (Same as [24] except view is taken a little more to the NE to show character of land on Sec. 36. A small stream runs just beyond the grove, left of center, which would afford a good domestic water supply. No water power. Ground rough and rocky. Tuesday, August 21 3:00 pm)
    - The Tetons, looking SW from Roan Horse Smith's place. (Box 9:7)
      (The Grand Teton on the right. This was examined as a possible campsite but the land is held at $25.00 per acre and there are other objections to this site. Tues., August 21 at 4:30 pm)
    - The Tetons, looking SW from Roan Horse Smith's place. (Box 9:7)
      (Same as 28, except with different stop and exposure. Tetons looking W from Roan Horse Smith's place. Tuesday, August 21)
    - A-Panorama, Jackson Lake and Tetons from Jackson Lake Lodge, SW, Tuesday, August 21, '28 [both lenses] (Box 9:7)
    - B-Panorama, W (Box 9:7)
    - C-Panorama, NW (Box 9:7)
    - A-Panorama, Jackson Lake and the Tetons from Lake Lodge, SW, Tuesday, August 21, '28 [front lens removed] (Box 9:7)
    - B-Panorama, W (Box 9:7)
    - C-Panorama, NW (Box 9:7)
    - The dam across Snake River at the outlet of Jackson Lake (Box 9:7)
      (Dam which converts the lake into a storage reservoir, 35 feet of water being held. View taken from south bank of river immediately below dam looking NW. Monday morning, August 20)
    - Mount Moran taken from a launch on Jackson Lake at a point about 8 miles W of dam, Monday, August 20 (Box 9:7)
    - Mount Moran taken from launch while returning toward dam. (Box 9:7)
      (An intervening hill or mountain covers the base of Mount Moran. Monday morning, August 20
    - Jennys Lake, Jackson Hole looking W from E shore of lake near the S end of lake Monday afternoon, August 20 (Box 9:7)
    - Leighs Lake, Jackson Hole, looking NW from E shore of lake near N end. Mount Moran at extreme right margin of view. Monday afternoon, August 20, '28 (Box 9:7)
    - Camp groups, 2 plates (Box 9:7)
      [55, 57]
- Glass Negatives
  - [Negatives for prints in box 8:1] (Box 1)
    [Staff use only]
  - [Negatives for prints in box 8:2] (Box 2)
  - [Negatives for prints in box 8:3] (Box 3)
  - [Negatives for prints in box 8:4] (Box 4)
  - [Negatives for prints in box 9:5] (Box 5)
  - [Negatives for prints in box 9:6] (Box 6)
  - [Negatives for prints in box 9:7] (Box 7)
- Biographical Material
  - Topical File
    - Art Cinema League (Box 10)
    - Brodie (Hugh) estate papers 1932-1936 (Box 10)
    - Committee on Engineering Degrees in the Latin American Republics 1916-1918 (Box 10)
    - Engineering Building Subcommittee 1921 (Box 10)
    - First Congregational Church, Ann Arbor 1916-1920 (Box 10)
    - Radio Talk and other speeches 1927 (Box 10)
    - Relicted Lands Commission 1929-1930 (Box 10)
    - Senate Council 1924-1926 (Box 10)
    - State Drain Commissioners Association 1918-1920 (Box 10)
    - Stipe (C.G.T.) correspondence (doctoral student) 1938-1941 (Box 10)
    - Student Christian Association 1917-1919 (Box 10)
    - Westside Mining Company, 1895, approximately 1915-1920 (Box 10)